[
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- Concert for Bangladesh, the first major benefit concert for a social cause, was organized by former Beatle George Harrison and Indian sitar player Ravi Shankar. What was the issue?",
        "correct": "Support for war refugees in East Pakistan",
        "answerA": "Support for war refugees in East Pakistan",
        "answerB": "Support for famine victims in southern India",
        "answerC": "Relief for victims of Hurricane Florence",
        "answerD": "Relief for victims of the AIDS crisis in Asia"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- The First Nations rap group called A Tribe Called Red is based in what country?",
        "correct": "Canada",
        "answerA": "Canada",
        "answerB": "New Zealand",
        "answerC": "Brazil",
        "answerD": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- How many studio albums did the 1980's and 90's Japanese noise rock band the Boredoms release?",
        "correct": "9",
        "answerA": "9",
        "answerB": "4",
        "answerC": "7",
        "answerD": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- This India based ska band recorded the anti-censorship song \"Badda\" in 2015.  ",
        "correct": "The Ska Vengers",
        "answerA": "The Ska Vengers",
        "answerB": "Reggae Rajahs",
        "answerC": "Swarathma",
        "answerD": "Tritha Electric"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- The UK based roots reggae band Steel Pulse won the Best Reggae Album Grammy in 1986 for what album?",
        "correct": "Babylon The Bandit",
        "answerA": "Babylon The Bandit",
        "answerB": "Babylon by Bus",
        "answerC": "Bye-Bye Babylon",
        "answerD": "Babylon- the Band"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- This rock steady, reggae and ska artist from Jamaica, had a number of socially- conscious hits in the 60's and 70's including \"Israelites,\" and \"You Can Get It If You Really Want.\"",
        "correct": "Desmond Dekker",
        "answerA": "Desmond Dekker",
        "answerB": "Lee Scratch Perry",
        "answerC": "Prince Buster",
        "answerD": "Alton Ellis"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- Kalakuta Records, a label out of Nigeria, released albums from this inventor of afro-beat from 1976-92.",
        "correct": "Fela Kuti",
        "answerA": "Fela Kuti",
        "answerB": "Burna Boy",
        "answerC": "Wizkid",
        "answerD": "Femi Kuti"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- The Wolfe Tones, a pro-republican, Irish folk band from Dublin, released several political albums  including Til Ireland a Nation and Up the Rebels on what label?",
        "correct": "Dolphin Records",
        "answerA": "Dolphin Records",
        "answerB": "Rebel Records",
        "answerC": "Fist Records",
        "answerD": "Shark Records"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- In 1964 this indigenous American record label released 12 Northern Cheyenne War Dance Songs.",
        "correct": "Indian Records",
        "answerA": "Indian Records",
        "answerB": "Native American Records",
        "answerC": "Indian Media Corporation",
        "answerD": "First Nations Music"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- A leading figure in the Nueva Trova movement in Cuba,  Silvo Rodriguez's music was recorded and distributed by this socially conscious, Mexican based record label.",
        "correct": "Discos Pueblo",
        "answerA": "Discos Pueblo",
        "answerB": "Univision Music Group",
        "answerC": "Nopal Beat Records",
        "answerD": "Disa Records"
    },
    {
        "question": "HALL OF NAMES- Who was the lead singer of the out- gay, 1980's synth-pop, dance band Bronski Beat?",
        "correct": "Jimmy Sommerville",
        "answerA": "Jimmy Sommerville",
        "answerB": "Bruce Wayne Campbell",
        "answerC": "Neil Tennant",
        "answerD": "Richard Coles"
    },
    {
        "question": "HALL OF NAMES- The socially conscious hip-hop act from Tennessee, Arrested Development, did a song in 1992 about a wise, homeless man. What was his name?",
        "correct": "Mr. Wendell",
        "answerA": "Mr. Wendell",
        "answerB": "Mr. Placer",
        "answerC": "Mr. Johnson",
        "answerD": "Mr. Jones"
    },
    {
        "question": "HALL OF NAMES- This UK pop star came out as gay in the late 70's and recorded the major hit \"Glad to Gay.\" What's his name? ",
        "correct": "Tom Robinson",
        "answerA": "Tom Robinson",
        "answerB": "Boy George",
        "answerC": "Billy Preston",
        "answerD": "Elton John"
    },
    {
        "question": "HALL OF NAMES- Tipper Gore, Susan Baker, Pam Howar, and Sally Nevius. These women were founding members of what Washington based organization in the 1980's?",
        "correct": "The Parents Music Resource Center",
        "answerA": "The Parents Music Resource Center",
        "answerB": "Washington Wives Against Indecency",
        "answerC": "Women Against Obscenity in Music",
        "answerD": "Mothers Against Drunk Driving"
    },
    {
        "question": "HALL OF NAMES- Where did Jello Biafra, the former lead singer for the Dead Kennedys, get his stage surname?",
        "correct": "A former country in east Nigeria",
        "answerA": "A former country in east Nigeria",
        "answerB": "A city in the country of Belize",
        "answerC": "A county in east Texas",
        "answerD": "A former country in coastal Chile"
    },
    {
        "question": "HALL OF NAMES- What's the name of the lead singer for the Providence, Rhode Island, punk band The Downtown Boys?",
        "correct": "Victoria Ruiz",
        "answerA": "Victoria Ruiz",
        "answerB": "Valeria Sanchez",
        "answerC": "Bobby Jordan",
        "answerD": "Michael Mitchell"
    },
    {
        "question": "YOU HAD TO BE THERE- The Hip-Hop artist Common did a series of concerts across the US in 2017 to highlight which issue?",
        "correct": "Mass Incarceration",
        "answerA": "Mass Incarceration",
        "answerB": "Police Accountability",
        "answerC": "Gun Control",
        "answerD": "Climate Change"
    },
    {
        "question": "YOU HAD TO BE THERE- The first Power to the Peaceful festival in 1999 in San Francisco was organized by Michael Franti in support of who?",
        "correct": "Mumia Abu-Jamal",
        "answerA": "Mumia Abu-Jamal",
        "answerB": "Sim√≥n Trinidad",
        "answerC": "Linda Evans",
        "answerD": "Kojo Bomani Sababu"
    },
    {
        "question": "YOU HAD TO BE THERE- Where was the first Farm Aid held in 1985?",
        "correct": "Champaign, Illinois",
        "answerA": "Champaign, Illinois",
        "answerB": "Lincoln, Nebraska",
        "answerC": "Kansas City, Kansas",
        "answerD": "Madera, California"
    },
    {
        "question": "YOU HAD TO BE THERE- The 1990's riot grrrl band Babes in Toyland started in what city?",
        "correct": "Minneapolis",
        "answerA": "Minneapolis",
        "answerB": "Tacoma",
        "answerC": "Dallas",
        "answerD": "Kansas City"
    },
    {
        "question": "YOU HAD TO BE THERE- After running into political opposition to its womens-only policy from the LGBTQI community, this music festival held its last event in August 2015.",
        "correct": "Michigan Womyn's Music",
        "answerA": "Michigan Womyn's Music",
        "answerB": "US Festival",
        "answerC": "Gathering of Tribes",
        "answerD": "Rainbow Music Festival"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- The Israeli punk band Useless ID contributed this song to the Fat Wreck Chords compilation Rock Against Bush, Vol. 2 in  2004.",
        "correct": "\"State of Fear\"",
        "answerA": "\"State of Fear\"",
        "answerB": "\"State of Dread\"",
        "answerC": "\"State of Hate\"",
        "answerD": "\"Cry of Love\""
    },
    {
        "question": "YOU HAD TO BE THERE- Who was the founder of the traveling music festival Lollapalooza which highlights alternative, punk and hip-hop artists, and gives progressive and leftist groups places to table?",
        "correct": "Perry Ferrell",
        "answerA": "Perry Ferrell",
        "answerB": "Bono",
        "answerC": "Geddy Lee",
        "answerD": "Kurt Cobain"
    },
    {
        "question": "YOU HAD TO BE THERE-The band Rage Against the Machine burned the American flag at this major rock festival in 1999.",
        "correct": "Woodstock 99",
        "answerA": "Woodstock 99",
        "answerB": "Ozzfest",
        "answerC": "Warped Tour",
        "answerD": "Riot Fest"
    },
    {
        "question": "HALL OF NAMES- Neil Young famously name drops this singer's name on the song \"Hey Hey, My My.\"",
        "correct": "Johnny Rotten",
        "answerA": "Johnny Rotten",
        "answerB": "Bob Marley",
        "answerC": "Joe Strummer",
        "answerD": "Prince"
    },
    {
        "question": "GLOBAL UPRISING- What is the name of the first million selling album by any artist?",
        "correct": "\"Calypso by Harry Belafonte released in 1956\"",
        "answerA": "\"Calypso by Harry Belafonte released in 1957\"",
        "answerB": "\"Hotel California by the Eagles in 1976\"",
        "answerC": "\"Here Comes the Sun\" by The Beatles in 1969",
        "answerD": "\"Shake, Rattle and Roll\" by Big Joe Turner in 1954"
    }
]